ruelala.com 2019-06-23

# Privacy Policy – Rue La La Customer Support

Rue La La is committed to protecting your privacy. At Rue La La, we want you to have an enjoyable shopping experience. And while it is necessary for us to collect certain personal information, we respect and protect your right to privacy as set forth in this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy applies to our websites (including ruelala.com), our mobile applications and related services (collectively, the "Services"). This Privacy Policy does not apply to other websites to which we link. You agree that your use of the Services signifies that you have read and consent to the collection, use and sharing of your information in accordance with this Privacy Policy,  **including the transfer to and storage of your personal information in the United States.**  If you do not agree with this Privacy Policy, you should not use the Services.

### INFORMATION COLLECTED

**User Provided Information**  -

Registration with us is mandatory in order to place orders and fully use the Services. During the registration process (whether on our website or through downloading the mobile application), we collect personal information such as your name, email address or social media user name. Once you register, you have opted in to receive electronic communications from us, unless you were prompted to indicate consent to such communications at the time of registration in accordance with the applicable law in the country where you reside.

We also collect personal information when you choose to use certain other aspects of the Services, such as making purchases; electing to receive text messages about upcoming boutiques; promotions or events; or if you provide it in response to surveys, contests, sweepstakes or other requests. When you choose to use these additional features, we may require you to provide additional personal information such as your phone number, billing and shipping addresses and credit card information, and we may request additional personal information such as your shopping preferences and demographics.

If you choose to invite an individual to join Rue La La, you will need to provide personal information about that individual, such as his/her name, email address or social media user name or provide us access to that information in your address book on a social networking site. We store this information to send and follow up on invitations to join Rue La La, provide information about the Services, confirm qualifying orders and other activities attributable to your account and track the results of the invitation referrals. You agree to invite only individuals who consent to be contacted for these purposes and you will not invite anyone who does not know you or who is unlikely to recognize you as a known contact.

We may collect other information that you submit to us or that you have consented to permit us to collect or third parties to share with us from time to time.

**Automatically Collected Information**  -

In addition, we use technologies such as pixels and JavaScript to automatically gather certain information about your use of the Services, such as your IP address, operating system, browser type and a date/stamp time for your visit. If you use our mobile applications, this may include information such geo-location data (e.g., through GPS, Bluetooth, Wi-Fi, or other means) and device information, such as your MAC address, for the handheld mobile device on which the mobile application is installed. We may also access your calendar to enable us to create and modify events on your behalf. We may also collect other information that you have consented to permit your mobile phone or application to share with us from time to time.

We may also gather information about how you interact with the Services, such as how frequently certain areas of our website or mobile application are visited, what products are reviewed and selected, order history, shipping program status, and other site navigation data and patterns. This information helps us to understand your interests and which aspects of our Services you find interesting.

**Involvement of Others in Data Collection**  -

We may work with third parties to collect and analyze the information as described above and for other purposes described below.

If you access our Services through other websites on which we have "stores" (e.g., eBay), we will collect and analyze the information described above that is obtained through your interaction with those websites. We may add this information to the information we have already collected from you via other aspects of the Services. You are also subject to such "store's" terms of use and privacy policy in connection with these Services.

If you access our Services with your login credentials from a social networking site (e.g., Facebook or Twitter) or if you otherwise agree to associate your Rue La La account with a social networking account, we may receive personal information about you from such social networking site, in accordance with the terms of use and privacy policy of the social networking site. For example, Facebook may share with us your friend list, birthday, information about the interests of you or your friends or other personal information, in order to help us establish your account, tailor the Services to you and find other current or potential Service users that you know. We may add this information to the information we have already collected from you via other aspects of the Service. You are also subject to the social networking site's terms of use and privacy policy. We use the OAuth (open authorization) protocol to enable us to access this information without collecting your password when you agree allow another application to access your account information.

Further, we may obtain information from others (including social media networks, advertising service providers and networks) that does not identify you personally or, if you have given that service or us permission to do so, information that identifies you personally. This information may be combined with information you have provided to us or that we or others have collected about you, so that we may maximize the benefit you receive from the Services and deliver advertising targeted to your specific interests on our websites and mobile applications and when you use other websites or mobile applications. Information about you also may be aggregated with other subscriber information for the purposes identified above.

**Use of Cookies**  -

We and our vendors may use technology such as cookies and web beacons in connection with these activities to identify you when you are online, and to collect information about your online activities, such as the type of browser you use, the websites you visit and the content and advertising that you find interesting. Cookies are small text files that may remain on your computer's hard drive for a period of time that may be used to maintain data relevant to your navigation of the Internet, save personal settings and information, and track web browsing habits. Web beacons are clear picture files that you cannot see that we use to monitor traffic and track your activities on the Internet.

The following is a description of the four categories of cookies and examples of how we use them to provide you the Services:

  * Strictly Necessary Cookies – These cookies are essential to enabling you to browse and use the functionality of a website and without them the Services cannot be provided. We use these cookies, among other things, to recognize and maintain your logged-in status throughout your visit and manage your shopping bag.
  * Performance Cookies – These cookies collect information about how visitors use the Services, for example, pages that they visit and if they receive error messages. This information does not identify you individually and is used in the aggregate to improve our Services.
  * Functionality Cookies – These cookies allow us to remember certain choices you make about how you like to use the Services and provide you a more personalized experience, for example, your shipping country and currency preferences.
  * Targeting Cookies – These cookies are used to deliver online advertisements that are relevant to you and your interests and to measure the effectiveness of advertising campaigns. They may be placed on the Services by us or by our advertising partners with our permission. For more on targeting cookies and your ability to control their use, please see the Internet-based Advertising section below.

You can restrict cookies through your browser’s cookie control settings. Each browser is a little different, but the most common browsers (Internet Explorer, Chrome, Firefox and Safari) have a preference or option you can select so that the browser notifies you if a site wants to set a cookie and typically provides an option to accept or reject the cookie before the cookie is set. If you choose to remove or reject cookies, it will affect many features on our websites and you may not be able to access certain aspects of the Services. For additional information about cookies, including how to refuse cookies, please visit: [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

We or our service providers may also use Flash cookies (also known as Local Stored Objects) or other similar technologies. A Flash cookie is a small data file placed on a computer using Adobe Flash or similar technology that may be built into your computer or downloaded or installed by you on your computer. We use these technologies to personalize and enhance your online experience, facilitate processes, and personalize and store your settings. Flash cookies may help our website visitors to, for example, set volume preference associated with a video experience, play games and perform surveys. They help us improve our websites by measuring which areas are of greatest interest to customers. They may be recognized by other websites or by our marketing or business partners. Flash cookies are different from browser cookies and the cookie management tools provided by your browser may not remove Flash cookies. To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies, visit <http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html>. If you disable Flash cookies or other similar technologies, please be aware that you may not have access to certain features and services that make your online experience more efficient and enjoyable.

By registering for and using the Services, you are consenting to the use of cookies. Because of the members-only nature of our Services, cookies are essential to the function of our websites and the provision of the Services. If you do not agree to the use of cookies, you cannot use the Services.

### HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION

We use the information we collect in several ways:

  * to give you a more enjoyable, convenient shopping experience, learn about your habits, personalize your user experience, and help us identify and/or provide information, products or services that may be of interest to you;
  * to support and enhance your use of the Services and their features, including without limitation: fulfilling your order; providing customer service; tracking email invitations you send; and otherwise supporting your use of the Services and its features;
  * to conduct market research, improve the Services and help us identify others who may be interested in the Services;
  * to serve you ads tailored to your interests or to tailor ads that may be served to you when you visit other websites, mobile applications or social media networks; and
  * in other ways for which we provide specific notice at the time of collection.

### HOW WE SHARE YOUR INFORMATION

We may share the information that you provide to us, and the information that we collect about you as described above, to others (including social media networks and advertising service providers and networks) to serve you ads tailored to your interests or to tailor ads that may be served to you on our website and mobile application, as well as other websites and mobile applications, and on social media networks.

We may permit certain trusted third parties to access your information in connection with their performance of services to maintain and operate our websites and mobile applications and certain features on the Services. For example, we may use third parties to host the websites and mobile applications; operate various features of the Services; send emails; analyze data; provide search results and links and assist in fulfilling your orders.

From time to time, we may share your personally identifiable information in connection with strategic relationships. Some of these strategic relationships may include operating a co-branded website or web pages with a strategic partner. You should be aware that these co-branded sites may collect different or additional information. Additionally, we may provide links to websites controlled by third parties. We have no control over these websites and our privacy policy does not apply to these third party websites. Please consult the privacy policy of the website you are visiting.

Also, we may share personally identifiable or other information with our parent, subsidiaries, divisions, and affiliates and across our various websites, apps and social media pages. Rue La La is a division of Retail Convergence.com, LP.

Occasionally, we provide our postal mailing list (consisting of customer names and postal mailing addresses, but not email addresses) to other companies for purposes of marketing the Services or other products or services that may be of interest to you. In order to determine the information that may be of interest to you, the information that you give us and information about your order may be combined with other personally identifiable information (such as demographic information and past purchase history) available from our records and other sources.

We may transfer personally identifiable information as an asset in connection with a proposed or actual merger or sale (including any transfers made as part of an insolvency or bankruptcy proceeding) involving all or part of our business or as part of a corporate reorganization, stock sale or other change in control.

We reserve the right to disclose information in order to comply with a subpoena, court order, administrative or governmental order, or any other requirement of law, or when we, in our sole discretion, believe it is necessary in order to protect our rights or the rights of others, to prevent harm to persons or property, to fight fraud and credit risk reduction.

If you post, use a bulletin board, chat room or any other publicly accessible area of our websites or mobile applications, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected or used by any person for any purpose. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable or other information you choose to submit in these forums.

We use non-personally identifiable information in the aggregate, so that we can improve our Services and for business and administrative purposes. We may also use or share with third parties for any purpose aggregated data that contains no personally identifiable information.

### CROSS-BORDER TRANSFER OF YOUR INFORMATION

Except as expressly provided herein, this is a U.S. website subject to U.S. laws, including those governing privacy and data security, and we will protect your information as described in this Privacy Policy. When we obtain information about you, we and our service providers and partners may process the information outside of the country where you are located, including in the U.S. These countries may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you are located and such information may be available to government authorities under lawful orders and as applicable in such foreign jurisdictions. You consent to any such cross-border transfer of your personal information.

### CHOICE AND OPT-OUT

We offer you certain choices about the collection, use and sharing of your information:

**Marketing Communications**  \- You may choose not to receive marketing email communications from us by clicking on the unsubscribe link in the marketing emails. You may change your email address for receipt of such communications by going to My Account. You may choose to opt out of receiving marketing communications through our mobile app notifications and text notifications in the manner identified when you opt in to receive those notifications.

**Location Data**  \- When you use our mobile applications, you may be able to choose not to share your location data by adjusting the applicable settings on your mobile device (the manufacturer or your service provider should be able to provide assistance). For additional information regarding location data and tracking, including how it may be used and how you may be able to opt out of or otherwise avoid tracking by many third-party mobile analytics firms, visit <https://smart-places.org/> and <https://www.networkadvertising.org/mobile-choices>.

**Data Analytics**  \- As disclosed above, we use automated devices and applications, such as Google Analytics, to evaluate usage of our websites. These third parties (and third-party devices and applications) may use cookies, web beacons, or other tracking technologies, as described above, in performing these services. If you do not wish to have technology used to gather information about how you interact with the Services while you are on our websites, please see the Interest-Based Advertising section below to learn how you can restrict the use of cookies in your browser and other tracking technologies. For more information on how Google Analytics collects and processes data, please visit <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/>.

**Interest-Based Advertising**  \- As noted above, we may use the information you provide to us, and information we collect about your use of our products and services, to assist us and our partners in our effort to deliver you online advertising that is relevant to your interests. In connection with these activities, we may work with social media networks and advertising service providers who help deliver these ads to you.

Our advertising service providers may also use cookies, web beacons and similar technologies to collect and track information such as demographic information, aggregated information, and Internet activity to assist them in delivering advertising that is more relevant to your interests.

There are several actions you can take to opt out of receiving targeted online advertising in this manner. To generally unsubscribe from advertiser cookies, please visit [www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) and [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) and follow the instructions on how to opt out. For instructions on how to specifically opt out of Criteo advertising services, please view the Criteo Privacy Policy at [www.criteo.com/us/privacy-policy](http://www.criteo.com/us/privacy-policy).

Please also note that most opt-out mechanisms are cookie-based, so you must have cookies enabled in your web browser, and they will only affect the specific computer and browser that is used to submit an opt-out request. If you have multiple computers or change computers, or use multiple browsers, you will need to submit opt-out requests for each such computer or browser. Once you opt out, if you delete your browser’s saved cookies, you will need to opt out again. Mobile devices may involve unique advertising choice mechanisms. For more information, please see the Location Data section above.

Note that opt-out mechanisms provided by third-parties or depending on your browser are not controlled by us, and we cannot guarantee their effectiveness. For more information on cookies, see above INFORMATION COLLECTED, Use of cookies.

### ACCESSING,UPDATING, AND DELETING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION AND PREFERENCES

We respect your right to access and correct your personal information. If you are a registered user, you may access and update your registration information through your MyAccount page. You may also manage your preferences to receive email or other communications from us by sending an email to [atyourservice@ruelala.com](mailto:atyourservice@ruelala.com). Please note that your friends and contacts may still choose to send email invitations to you. Any user who receives an email invitation to register may choose not to receive such invitations in the future by following the instructions in the email invitations and, in addition, if you are a member, you may also choose not to receive such invitations by changing your preferences as indicated above. We will take commercially reasonable steps to implement your opt-out requests promptly, but you may still receive communications from us for up to ten business days as we process your request.

You may also exercise your rights, subject to applicable laws, to request that we delete or restrict access to your personal data. We may need to retain data for legally permitted purposes and this will be explained to you if necessary.

### HOW WE PROTECT YOUR INFORMATION

We are committed to protecting the information we receive from you. We follow reasonable technical and management practices to help protect the confidentiality, security and integrity of data stored on our system. While no computer system is completely secure, we believe the measures we have implemented reduce the likelihood of security problems to a level appropriate to the type of data involved.

Your credit card and other personal information is protected using secure socket layer (SSL) or similarly secure technology to provide for the secure transmission of the information from your PC or device. In addition, only those employees and third parties who need access to your information in order to perform their duties are allowed such access.

We also require you to enter a password to access your account. We recommend that you not disclose your password to unauthorized people.

### DATA RETENTION

Personal information that we collect, access or process will be retained only so long as necessary for the fulfillment of the purposes for which it was collected, as necessary for our legitimate business purposes, or as required or authorized by law. Personal information that is no longer required to fulfil the identified purposes will be destroyed, erased or made de-identified or anonymous.

### RIGHT TO LODGE COMPLAINTS

We are transparent about the ways in which we collect and use personal information and welcome your questions and concerns. If you have any concern or complaint about the way we handle your personal information, please contact us at [Legal@RueLaLa.com](mailto:Legal@RueLaLa.com). To the extent you believe we have not addressed your concerns or otherwise choose to do so, you have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority in the country where you reside and/or the United States. You may contact the US Federal Trade Commission regarding your concerns. For more information, please see <https://www.ftc.gov/faq/consumer-protection/submit-consumer-complaint-ftc>.

### CHILDREN'S PRIVACY AND PARENTAL CONTROLS

Our business is not directed at children, and we do not solicit or knowingly collect any personal information from children under the age of 13 without verifiable parental consent. If you are not 18 or older, you are not authorized to use the Services. Parents should be aware that there are parental control tools available online that you can use to prevent your children from submitting information online without parental permission or from accessing material that is harmful to minors.

### YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS

If you are a California resident, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits you to request information regarding the disclosure of your personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To request a list of the names and addresses of third parties to whom we disclosed such information during the preceding calendar year along with a list of the categories of information disclosed, please send an email to [Legal@RueLaLa.com](mailto:Legal@RueLaLa.com) or write to us at the following address:

Rue La La  
Legal Department  
20 Channel Center  
Boston, MA 02210

### PRIVACY POLICY CHANGES

If we decide to change this Privacy Policy, we will post the revised Privacy Policy here so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information and whether we may disclose it to anyone. Your continued use of the Services indicates your consent to the Privacy Policy as posted.

### HOW TO CONTACT US

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at:

Rue La La  
20 Channel Center  
Boston, MA 02210  
1-888-992-LALA (5252)  

Last Updated: May 24th, 2018  
© 2008 - 2018 Retail Convergence.com, LP. All rights reserved.
